(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
COVER
hololive
3rd Anniversary LIVE
Tsunomaki Watame
YAGOO
COVER Co., Ltd. CEO
Watame Rock Fes 2022
My Song
2022.12.29(Thu)
Watame Rock Fes 2022
My Song
Tsunomaki Watame
Today's star!
And 11 special guests...
Tokino Sora
AZKi
Mori Calliope
Tokoyami Towa
Shirogane Noel
みんなー！
Everyone!
3周年ライブ、遊びに来てくれてありがとうー！
Thank you for coming to my 3rd anniversary live!
楽しんでいきましょう！
Let's have some fun!
ワンダーランドと羊の歌
作詞・作曲 ハチ
Wonderland and the Sheep's Song
Lyrics & Composition: Hachi
何でもないような顔して犬をご機嫌損ねてバウワウと
With a nonchalant face, upsetting the dog, bow-wow
今日もレイニーデイ レイニーデイ
Another rainy day, rainy day
山の頂上で少女が泣き濡れてはリンゴ飴をなめて空を見た
A girl crying on a mountain peak, licking a candy apple and looking at the sky
今日もレイニーデイ レイニーデイ
Another rainy day, rainy day
カンテラ持って飾って
Holding and decorating a lantern
明日の準備を拵えて
Preparing for tomorrow
賛美の言葉を唱えよ
Chanting words of praise
ほらハイレディランド
Look, High Ready Land
魚の目で歌って
Singing with the eyes of a fish
有刺鉄線を飛び越えて
Jumping over the barbed wire
遊ぼうぜ
Let's play
笑おうぜ
Let's laugh
くだらない愛を歌うこの街の中
In this city where trivial love is sung
灯を灯せば何もない
If you light a lamp, there's nothing there
1 2 3 4 5 ほら合図で君に会いに行く
1 2 3 4 5, look, with the signal I'll go see you
新しい日を迎えに行こう
Let's go welcome a new day
（ラララ...）
(La la la...)
なんて名前かも忘れてまた赤電話鳴りフワフワと
Forgetting the name, the red phone rings again, floating along
今日もレイニーデイ レイニーデイ
Another rainy day, rainy day
煙草の煙に濡れちゃってまたむせ返る路地裏さて歩いてった
Soaked in cigarette smoke, choking in the back alley, I walked on
レイニーデイ レイニーデイ
Rainy day, rainy day
アンテナ立ったらもう一回
Once the antenna's up, one more time
商店街から顔出して
Peeking out from the shopping street
泣いてる子には唱えよ
Chant to the crying child
ほらハイレディランド
Look, High Ready Land
サヨナラばかり詰め込んで
Packed full of nothing but goodbyes
二律背反を背負い込んで
Shouldering antinomies
泣かないで
Don't cry
揺れないで
Don't waver
右手の上で回る地球儀を
The globe spinning on the right hand
左手の火で照らそうか
Shall we light it with the fire in the left hand?
空の色が変わるその時に
At that moment when the sky changes color
胸に残るのは君のこと
What remains in the heart is you
雨宿り駄菓子屋で
Sheltering from the rain at a candy store
神様の帰りを待った
Waiting for God to return
さあ歌おうか羊の歌
Now, shall we sing the sheep's song?
君の手のそのカンテラが
That lantern in your hand
全てを照らす太陽なんだ
Is the sun that illuminates everything
君が歌を歌うこの街の中
In this city where you sing a song
灯を灯せば素敵なこと
If you light a lamp, it's a wonderful thing
1 2 3 4 5 ほら合図で君に会いに行く
1 2 3 4 5, look, with the signal I'll go see you
新しい日を迎えに行こう
Let's go welcome a new day
トンネルの先には何がある
What lies at the end of the tunnel?
未知なる街の底に踏み出していく
Stepping into the bottom of an unknown city
1 2 3 4 5 ほら合図で君に会いに行く
1 2 3 4 5, look, with the signal I'll go see you
新しい日を迎えに行こう
Let's go welcome a new day
（ラララ...）
(La la la...)
ラララ...
La la la...
最後まで盛り上がって行きましょう！
Let's keep the energy up until the end!
本当にありがとう！
Thank you so much!
dawn
作詞: LiSA 作曲: 草野華余子 / 堀江晶太
Lyrics: LiSA Composition: Kayoko Kusano / Shota Horie
無数に広がる　夢と願いが
Countless dreams and wishes spread out,
夜に飲み込まれ　姿を消してく
Are swallowed by the night and disappear.
試されている　この答えと
The answer and my resolve
僕の覚悟は本物か
Are being tested to see if they're real.
喜びを吸い込んで　不安を吐き出して
Breathe in the joy, breathe out the anxiety,
生かされてる意味を　ずっと探してんだよ
I've been searching for the meaning of being alive.
たとえ独り言に　なったとしても
Even if it just becomes a monologue,
これが僕の　確かな光と祈り
This is my certain light and prayer.
誠実に生きることで
By living honestly,
強くなれると信じて
Believing I can become stronger.
見逃すな day by day
Don't miss it, day by day.
彷徨い　彷徨い　幾つもの日々を
Wandering, wandering, I've overtaken
追い越したんだ
So many days.
生き残ったこの世界で
In this world where I survived,
新しい　眩しい　幕開けを
To a new, dazzling beginning,
迎えに行こうか
Shall we go to meet it?
愛すべきはずの　大事なものが
The precious things that should be loved
僕ららしさを　また一つ崩してく
Break down our uniqueness once again.
守ると決めた　この正義が
This justice I've decided to protect,
時を誰かを　傷つけてしまおうとも
Even if it ends up hurting someone or time.
涙を飲み干して　幸せ噛み締めて
Drink up your tears, savor your happiness,
この存在の意味を　ほら
The meaning of this existence, look,
味わいながら
As I savor it.
例えば全てが　ゼロになっても
Even if everything becomes zero,
ありのままと　本音に戻るだけ
I'll just return to my true self and feelings.
重ねた step by step
Accumulated step by step.
すれ違い　間違い　傷付いてもまた
Passing by, mistakes, even if hurt,
ここに立ってんだ
I'm standing here again.
悩み抜いたその先で
Beyond all the worries,
悔やまない　逃げない　ただ一つの
The one and only way for me,
僕のやり方
Without regrets or running away.
見逃すな day by day
Don't miss it, day by day.
彷徨い　彷徨い　幾つもの日々を
Wandering, wandering, I've overtaken
追い越したんだ
So many days.
生き残ったこの世界で
In this world where I survived,
新しい　眩しい　幕開けを
To a new, dazzling beginning,
迎えに行こう
Let's go to meet it.
巡り巡る view で
In the cycling view,
泣いても　逃げても　幸せをいつも
Even if I cry or run away, I always
願っていたい
Want to keep wishing for happiness.
いつか終わるその日まで
Until the day it eventually ends,
新しい　眩しい　幕開けを
To a new, dazzling beginning,
迎えに行こうか
Shall we go to meet it?
おー、こんばん、どどどど！
Oh, good evening, dodododo!
わー、すごいねー、広いねー。
Wow, it's amazing, it's so big!
角巻わため三周年ということで、
Since it's Tsunomaki Watame's 3rd anniversary,
今日は、ずっとやりたかった野外ロックフェスをやらせていただきます！
today, I'm holding the outdoor rock festival I've always wanted to do!
にゃーい！
Nyai!
今日のハッシュタグわかる人ー！
Who knows today's hashtag?!
わかんないのかなー？
Maybe you don't know?
わかる人いないのかなー？
Is there no one who knows?
わためわかる、わかる、わかる！
Watame knows, knows, knows!
はい、わためちゃん、はい！
Yes, Watame-chan, here!
えー、今日はですねー、
Um, so today...
こちら！
it's this!
ハッシュタグ、わたフェス。
Hashtag: #わたフェス (Wata-Fes).
わたフェス。
Wata-Fes.
Repeat after me. わたフェス。
Repeat after me. Wata-Fes.
とてもわかりやすいですね。
It's very easy to understand, isn't it?
このわたフェスを付けて、えー、スクショとかもね、いっぱい撮って、
Please use this #わたフェス and take lots of screenshots,
いっぱいバシバシあげていただければ、後でね、わためが見ますんで、
and post them. Watame will check them out later,
よろしくお願いいたします！
so please do!
そして、こちら！
And, here's this!
今日は見せたいものがある。
I have something I want to show you today.
ぽい！
Poi!
あー、こんばんどどど、町内のみなさん。
Ah, good evening dodo, everyone in the neighborhood.
今日はわたロックフェス2022がありますんで、
The Wata-Rock Fes 2022 is happening today,
お集まりください、今すぐに！
so please gather around, right now!
ということでね、この拡声器を今日この時のために作っていただきました！
So, this megaphone was made specifically for today!
えー、でもね、この後アフターライブまで、えー、使う機会がございませんので、
But, since I won't have another chance to use it until the after-live,
よろしくお願いいたします、アフターライブ来てください。
please come to the after-live later.
では置きます。
Now, I'll put it down.
よっこいしょ。
Heave-ho.
ふぅ。
Phew.
この後、ゲストパートもありますんで、
There's a guest segment coming up next,
みんな盛り上がっていけるかー！
so is everyone ready to get excited?!
もっともっともっと！
More, more, more!
ゲスト来るんだぞ！
The guests are coming!
もっともっとー！
More, more!
コメント打てー！
Type your comments!
いいね、あったまったね。
Nice, we're warmed up now.
ほな、ぶち上がっていくぜ！
Now, let's turn it up!
8, 7, 6, 5, 4, 3, 2, 1!
mind as Judgment
名もなき暗都(くらと) 旅人の 闇をかき回せ The feel
Stir up the darkness of a nameless city traveler, The feel
蘇る魔の群れ
The awakening horde of demons
淀みの境目 手招いて 時の果てまで Stand up
Beckon to the edge of stagnation, until the end of time, Stand up
死神の笑い声
The laughter of the Grim Reaper
汚れ果てても 贖っても 抗い続けては
No matter how stained or redeemed, keep resisting
Did you see? Did you see?
秘めたエンブレム
The hidden emblem
守るべき命 抱いて 重さが痛いと信じてた
Holding a life worth protecting, believing the weight was painful
堕落への駆け引き でも裏切りならば
The bargaining with corruption, but if it's betrayal...
Trust of heart 大事な世界
Trust of heart, a precious world
暮れる夜は身 迷い込ませ
Letting the body wander into the twilight night
mind as Judgment
Give up!
祈りを灰に 戯れ言は 荒れた孤独の Off design
Turning prayers into ashes, jokes are the off-design of a desolate loneliness
溺れる者たちへ
To those who are drowning
脆き光 明けぬ夜 すがりつく手の絶叫
Fragile light, endless night, the scream of hands clinging on
断末魔の叫び声
The death-throes scream
蠢いてる 囁いてる 欲の香り 撒き散らし
Wriggling, whispering, spreading the scent of desire
Those fake Those fake
選びなさい
Choose
滅びの日が来る定めに 言葉に意味さえ無いのなら
In the destiny where the day of ruin arrives, if words lose their meaning...
あなたから唱えて 今 切実な願い
...chant it yourself now, a sincere wish
Keep your face 蔑むべきは
Keep your face, what should be despised...
諦めの精神(こころ)
...is the spirit of resignation
mind as Judgment
NIGHTLESS WANDERER
残り少ないさ 逃げたらどこへ 恐れ満ちて
There's little left, so where to go if you run? Filling with fear...
咆哮 まって 呼びまぜ
A roar, wait, call out and mix together.
Seven!
Six!
Five!
Four!
Three!
Two!
One!
Secret Weapon!
滅びの日がくる定めに 言葉に意味さえないのなら
If it's our fate for the day of ruin to come, and words no longer have meaning,
あなたから唱えて 今切実な願い
Then you be the one to chant a heartfelt wish now.
無垢な命抱いて 重さが愛なのか
Embracing innocent life, is that weight what love is?
私の姿 まだ裏切る前の
My form, from before I've even betrayed it...
Just of heart 大事な世界
Just of heart, this precious world.
見つめながら
While staring at it...
mind as Judgment
Get out! Get out!
I shout! I shout!
Get out!
イェーイ！
Yeah!
嬉しい！嬉しい！
I'm so happy! I'm so happy!
わため三周年おめでとう！ おめでとう！
Happy 3rd anniversary, Watame! Congratulations!
おめでとう！嬉しいんじゃあ〜。
Congratulations! I'm so happy~.
AZKiちゃんも、そらちゃんも、来てくれてありがとうございます。
AZKi-chan, Sora-chan, thank you both for coming.
こちらこそ。抱きしめちゃう。
Same here. I'm going to hug you.
え、いい？いい！イェーイ！
Wait, really? Yes! Yeah!
ラムサンドです。ラムサンドです。
It's a lamb sandwich. It's a lamb sandwich.
これはラムサンド？ サンドイッチです。
Is this a lamb sandwich? It's a sandwich.
スクショタイム！スクショタイム！
Screenshot time! Screenshot time!
イェーイ！
Yeah!
嬉しい。いいな、ラムサンド美味しそう。
I'm happy. That lamb sandwich looks delicious.
美味しいよ。
It's delicious.
食べちゃうぞ。食べちゃうぞ。
I'm gonna eat you. I'm gonna eat you.
おかしいんだよな。二人ならいいか。
That's weird... but I guess if it's you two, it's fine.
熱い！ヤバイ！嬉しい！
Hot! Amazing! I'm so happy!
ヤバイね。どう？
Amazing. How is it?
すごい素敵な野外ステージ。嬉しいステージだ！
Such a wonderful outdoor stage. A happy stage!
わためぇとがギターとベースとドラムを、そう、担当している。
The Watamates are handling the guitar, bass, and drums.
ちょっと会いに...
Gonna go see them...
え、行ってくれんの？わためぇと！
Wait, are you going? Watamate!
わためぇと！可愛い！
Watamate! So cute!
嬉しいね。そして、そして、こっちだ！
I'm happy. And and, this way!
ベース！これ、パリピ眼鏡かけて。
Bass! He's wearing Haripi glasses.
髪もね、決まってるでしょ。決めてるんですよ。
His hair is also perfectly set, right? He's all set.
キメキメてんねん。キメてんねん。嬉しいね。
He's totally styled. Totally styled. Happy.
そして、この後ろに、ドラムの...
And behind us, the drum...
ドラムのわためぇと！わためぇと！イェーイ！
The drum Watamate! Watamate! Yeah!
そして会場にもいっぱいいますね、わためぇとさん。
And there are lots of Watamates in the audience too.
ね。わためぇと！イェーイ！
Right. Watamate! Yeah!
素敵なステージに来れて嬉しい。
I'm happy to be on such a wonderful stage.
嬉しい。この曲もね、歌いたかったんで。絶対合うと思ってさ。
I'm happy. I wanted to sing this song too. I thought it would definitely fit.
嬉しい。知ってた？この曲。
I'm happy. Did you know this song?
初めてだった。
It was my first time.
初めて歌った。わためちゃんが教えてくれて。めちゃくちゃいい曲でしたね。
I sang it for the first time. Watame-chan taught it to us. It was a really great song.
覚えてくれたの？
You learned it for me?
そうなの。ありがとう。コーラスとかね、ハモリも結構いっぱいあって。
Yes. Thank you. There were a lot of choruses and harmonies.
事前に頑張ってきました。
We worked hard on it beforehand.
頑張ったね。ありがとうございました。
We did our best. Thank you very much.
手伝っていただいてありがとうございます。素敵なステージになりました。
Thank you for helping me. It became a wonderful stage.
嬉しい！素晴らしいね、三周年だ！
Happy! It's wonderful, it's the 3rd Anniversary!
早いね。すごいね。
It's been fast. Amazing.
え、また歌ってくれる？
Hey, will you sing with us again?
是非是非！いいな、この赤、黄色、青で信号機みたいな。
Definitely! It's nice, this red, yellow, and blue, like a traffic light.
信号機！いいやん！
Traffic light! Nice!
やろうよ、また一緒に。
Let's do it together again.
よろしくお願いします！
Please look forward to it!
ありがとうね、このあともね...
Thank you, for what's coming next...
頑張ります！ありがとう！
I'll keep doing my best! Thank you!
Next guest, Calli!
Reaper vs. Sheep -Ouen ver.-
A Reaper's playin' for keeps
so Reaper said that I swing
Make a believer outta doubt
as I become the King
It's a battle, yeah, you shouldn't leave the rappin' to me
Goro-Goro the Wolf was hungry for her Senpai the Sheep
毎日がエモい死、数年で最高マジ
Every day is an emotional death, best few years for real.
でも本物のラッパーならばまずはディスは禁
But if you're a real rapper, first of all, disses are forbidden.
わため先輩、いこうぜ！
Watame-senpai, let's go!
I used to raise 'em up for rust
but guess I'll give it a shot
Exclusive's go in the trash
so get the elbows to get
A script of tearing a curse
from Calli's next at the bat
Gonna kick that shit in reverse
I'm wishin' it crushed your boy flat!
背中押すだけならほらね簡単でしょ
Just giving a push is easy, see?
お腹から声出してまずは応援っしょ
Sing from your stomach and cheer first!
観客が決めるこれがGOOD or BAD
The audience decides if it's GOOD or BAD
いくぜ 3, 2, 1!
Let's go! 3, 2, 1!
悩んで悩んでもいいんだぜ
It's okay to worry and worry
別に悪くないよね
It's not bad at all, is it?
迷って迷っても頑張れ
Even if you're lost, do your best
って言わなくちゃないよね
That's what I have to say
The Reaper and Sheep off the best for you
明日も明後日もそばに居よ
I'll be by your side tomorrow and the next day
笑って笑ってもいいんだぜ
It's okay to laugh and laugh
笑われるまで泣いたれ
Cry until you get laughed at
Cops hangin' what the melon
aren't you feelin' the heat?
Coz when it comes to rappin'
compliments on the wrap of the beat
Gotta let you know that your flow
was lookin' so pro and the bars that you sittin'
are fire isn't it funny
they want me to kill 'em with kindness
I'll never get tired
はっ倒してご機嫌な羊の変
Knock 'em down, the sheep's odd good mood
吐く言葉皮肉 良くないね
Spitting ironic words, that's not good
つまり愛ですらも
In other words, even love
気持ちよくさせるフローがまずは欲しいの
I want a flow that feels good first
今のわためて わざとわためて
The current Watame, intentionally Watame
He's a track of fact
you made 'em down on my knees
God damn it take it all back
the sheep has got so much cheese
Hold up that shit's kind of cringe
it's just a meme and the please
Your line's the baddest illest
phrase of any English and making your victory a breeze
ありがとう満ちる私もありがもって思うわ
Thank you, I'm full, I also think I'm grateful
わためのラップが最高だから
Because Watame's rap is the best
麻婆豆腐も食べたいし
I want to eat Mapo Tofu too
わための勝ちってことでいいかな？
So it's okay to say Watame wins?
YEAH!
HEY! HEY! HEY!
Hands up!
Put your hands up, and YEAH!
楽しんでますかー！
Are you having fun?!
Alright, let's go!
Bring it in everybody!
Okay, time to get serious.
When playing it's time to get slain
all praise and I raise it to debt
be surprisin' they prayin' the lines to be lamb
betray me, flame me, open and live
maybe death we be low-key nobody best
tryna mess with the sheep but she makes a cut
she'll be cut cute deep more than once
she push your buttons so honestly
Watame ought to be taking the lead!
本気のためラップかまします まずは何がいい？
Dropping a serious rap, what should I start with?
どんどん集まってくる視線の先は巻きたい
The focus of the gathering eyes is on me
変態全開させ先輩 限界宴会いくぜ！
Letting my perversion out, Senpai, let's go to the limit!
3, 2, 1!
悩んで悩んでもいいんだぜ
It's okay to worry and worry
別に悪くないよね
It's not bad at all, is it?
迷って迷っても頑張れ
Even if you're lost, do your best
って言わなくちゃないよね
That's what I have to say
The Reaper and Sheep off the best for you
明日も明後日もそばに居よ
I'll be by your side tomorrow and the next day
笑って笑ってもいいんだぜ
It's okay to laugh and laugh
笑われるまで泣いたれ
Cry until you get laughed at
One more time! One more time!
No no no...
わため先輩、もう終わりですよ。
Watame-senpai, it's over now.
えー！まだまだラップし足りないよ！
Ehh! I haven't rapped enough yet!
Round 2 いけるよね？
We can do Round 2, right?
死神だけど... dammit...
I'm a Reaper but... dammit...
はーい！いえーい！
Haii! Yay!
すごかったね！ありがとうみんな！
That was amazing! Thanks everyone!
楽しかったー！カリちゃん来てくれてありがとー！
That was fun! Thanks for coming, Calli-chan!
はー、毎回楽しいね、わため先輩。
Ah, it's fun every time, Watame-senpai.
ね！
Right!
本当に誘ってくれて、ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much for inviting me.
こちらこそ！
Likewise!
カリちゃんのソロライブの時も、呼んでくれてありがとうございました。
Thank you for inviting me to your solo live too.
もちろんです。
Of course.
いつでもね、呼んでくださいね。
Please invite me anytime, okay?
そして素敵な3周年、おめでとうございます！
And congratulations on a wonderful three years!
ありがとー！嬉しい！
Thank you! I'm happy!
うわー、めっちゃめっちゃ素晴らしい先輩、
Wow, you're a really amazing senior,
本当に憧れな人です、わため先輩。
someone I truly admire, Watame-senpai.
大好き。
I love you.
えー！照れるー。
Ehh! I'm blushing.
わためも大好き！嬉しい、あはっ。
I love you too! I'm happy, haha.
嬉しい... はぁ、ドキドキしてる。
I'm happy... Ah, my heart is pounding.
I love you.
I love you too, senpai!
I love you too, Calliope-senpai!
いつもうわーって頑張ってるね、先輩。
You're always working so hard, senpai.
そんなことない、カリちゃんたって。
Not at all, you too Calli-chan.
いや、本当に何かすごいリスペクトしてるよ。
No, I really respect you a lot.
こちらこそ、Very Busy Reaperだ。
Likewise, Very Busy Reaper.
No, Very Busy Sheep.
これからもね、ラップでも歌でも頑張りましょう。
Let's keep doing our best in rap and singing.
頑張りましょう！そうだね、sheep rapper。
Let's do our best! That's right, sheep rapper.
そう、でも次回ね、負けないよ。
Yes, but next time, I won't lose.
いえ、次も勝ちます！勝ちますね、次も。
No, I'll win next time too! I'll win next time as well.
No, 勝ちますよ！
No, I'll win!
絶対勝つ！
I'll definitely win!
やだね！え、でもじゃあ次も歌ってくれるってこと？
No way! Oh, but does that mean you'll sing with me next time too?
Round 2! Round 2! 2, 2, 2!
もうちょっと何かスタミナトレーニングしなきゃいけない。
I need to do a bit more stamina training.
あは、Very Busy Reaperだね。
Haha, I'm a Very Busy Reaper.
そうだね。運動したいよ。頑張ります、先輩。
That's right. I want to exercise. I'll do my best, Calliope-senpai.
わかった。また次一緒に歌おう。
Understood. Let's sing together again next time.
もちろんです。
Of course.
あ、呼んでくださいね、いつでも。
Ah, please invite me anytime.
ありがとうだよ。嬉しい。はーい、じゃあ頑張ってね。
Thank you. I'm happy. Okay, keep doing your best.
頑張る！はーい、ありがとう！
I will! Yes, thank you!
ありがとう本当にみんな！See you!
Thank you so much everyone! See you!
Habit
作詞：Fukase 作曲：Nakajin
Lyrics: Fukase Composition: Nakajin
君たちったら何でもかんでも分類、区別、ジャンル分けしたがる
You guys always want to classify, distinguish,
and categorize everything.
人はなぜか分類したがる習性があるとかないとか
People supposedly have an instinct to categorize,
whether that's true or not.
この世の中には2種類の人間がいるとか言う君たちが標的
You who say there are two types of people
in this world are the targets.
持ってる奴と持ってない奴とか ちゃんとやる奴とやってない奴とか
Those who have and those who don't,
those who do it right and those who don't.
陰キャ陽キャ君ら分類しないとどうにも落ち着かない
Introverts, extroverts... you can't relax
unless you categorize them.
気付かない本能の外側を覗いていかない？気分が乗らない
Won't you look outside the instinct you don't
notice? You're not in the mood.
つまりそれはそんなシンプルじゃない
In other words, it's not that simple.
もっと曖昧で繊細で不明瞭な何か
Something more vague, delicate, and obscure.
例えば持ってるのに出せない奴 やってるのにイケない奴
For example, those who have it but can't show it,
those who do it but can't succeed.
持ってるのに悟ったフリしてスカしてるうちに不安になっちゃったりする奴
Those who have it but act enlightened,
only to become anxious while being smug.
所詮あんたはギフテッド 私は普通の主婦ですと
After all, you're gifted, while I'm just
a regular housewife.
それは言い逃れ、素晴らしい逃げ、不可能の証明の加勢なんじゃない？
Isn't that an excuse, a great escape,
supporting the proof of impossibility?
夢を持てなんて言ってない そんな無責任になりはしない
I'm not saying to have a dream.
I won't be that irresponsible.
ただその習性に喰われないで
Just don't be consumed by that instinct.
そんなハビット捨てるたび見えてくる君の価値
Every time you discard that habit,
your true value becomes visible.
俺たちだって動物 こういうのって好物
We're animals too, and we love this kind of thing.
ここまで言われたらドーパ、腹の底からコウブツブツ
After being told this much, dopamine peaks
and I'm grumbling from deep inside.
俺たちだって動物 ゆえに持つオリジナルな習性
We're animals too, hence we have our own
unique instincts.
自分で自分を分類するなよ 壊して見せろよそのバッド・ハビット
Don't categorize yourself.
Break that bad habit and show me.
壊して見せろよそのバッド・ハビット
大人の俺が言っちゃいけないこと言っちゃうけど説教するってぶっちゃけ快楽
As an adult, I shouldn't say this,
but honestly, preaching is a pleasure.
酒の肴にすりゃもう傑作でも目的見失うきっかけ
It's a masterpiece when paired with drinks,
but it can cause you to lose sight of your goal.
になれりゃそれはそれでウィンウィンじゃん
If it becomes that, it's a win-win, isn't it?
これってこれって残念じゃん
Isn't this, isn't this just unfortunate?
そもそもそれって君次第だし
In the first place, that's up to you.
その後なんか俺興味ないわけ
I'm not interested in what happens after.
この先君はどうしたい？って人に問われること自体
Being asked 'What do you want to do now?'
by others in itself...
終わりじゃないと信じたいけどそうじゃなきゃかなり非常事態
I want to believe it's not the end,
but otherwise, it's quite an emergency.
君たちがその分類された普通の箱で燻ってるからさ
Because you guys are smoldering
in those categorized 'normal' boxes.
俺は人生イージーモードずっとそこで眠っててやりなよ
My life is on easy mode. Just stay asleep
there forever.
俺はそもそもスペックが低いだから足掻いて藻掻いて醜く吠えた
My specs were low to begin with, so I struggled,
writhed, and howled uglily.
俺のあの頃を分類したら誰の目から見ても明らか
If you categorized me back then,
it would be obvious to anyone's eyes.
すぐ世の中金だとか愛だとか運だとか縁だとか
Immediately saying the world is about money,
love, luck, or destiny.
わずか二文字で片付けちゃうの
Sorting it out with just a few characters.
俺たちはもっと曖昧で
We are much more vague,
複雑で不明瞭な何か
complex, and obscure things.
悟ったフリして奢るなよ
Don't be arrogant by acting enlightened.
君に君を分類する能力なんてない
You don't have the ability to categorize yourself.
俺たちだって動物 こういうのって好物
We're animals too, and we love this kind of thing.
ここまで言われたらドーパ、腹の底からコウブツブツ
After being told this much, dopamine peaks
and I'm grumbling from deep inside.
俺たちだって動物 ゆえに持つオリジナルな習性
We're animals too, hence we have our own
unique instincts.
自分で自分を分類するなよ 壊して見せろよそのバッド・ハビット
Don't categorize yourself.
Break that bad habit and show me.
俺たちだって動物 こういうのって好物
We're animals too, and we love this kind of thing.
ここまで言われたらドーパ、腹の底からコウブツブツ
After being told this much, dopamine peaks
and I'm grumbling from deep inside.
俺たちだって動物 ゆえに持つオリジナルな習性
We're animals too, hence we have our own
unique instincts.
自分で自分を分類するなよ 壊して見せろよそのバッド・ハビット
Don't categorize yourself.
Break that bad habit and show me.
壊して見せろよそのバッド・ハビット
次のゲストは！
The next guests are...
ルイちゃん！ノエルちゃん！カモーン！
Lui-chan! Noel-chan! Come on!
どーもー！お邪魔します！
Hello! Pardon the intrusion!
3周年おめでとうございます！
Happy 3rd anniversary!
おめでとー！ありがとうございます！
Congrats! Thank you!
ということで、この3人で今日はコントをね、やらせていただきたいなと思います！
So, the three of us would like to
perform a skit today!
タイトル名言ってもいいですか？
Can I say the title?
はい、お願いします。
Yes, please.
タイトル名、「シナジーなし」。
The title is... "No Synergy".
なんでやねん！あるだろ！あるだろうよ！
What the heck! We have it!
We have synergy!
ありまっす？
Do we have synergy?
だって... まぁ、女騎士、女幹部、女羊ぐらい。
Well, we have a female knight, executive, and sheep.
そうだね。女って付きゃ...
Right. If you just add "female"...
何でもいいみたい。女シナジーはちょっと...
Seems like anything goes. "Female synergy" is a bit...
ダメ？
No good?
でも、うち等ただの羊... 食べ物になったらいいんじゃない？
But we're just sheep...
Wouldn't it be fine if we became food?
食べ物になったら？
If we became food?
ラム牛丼とか...
Like a lamb beef bowl...
牛丼！あ、シナジー生まれたよ！
Beef bowl! Oh, synergy was born!
あ、生まれた！生まれたよ！
Oh, it's born! It's born!
無理矢理... 牛丼なのか羊なのか...
You're forcing it...
Is it a beef bowl or a sheep...
じゃ、私がそれをね、調理すれば...
Then, if I cook it...
あ！シナジー！料理に来た！
Ah! Synergy! She came to cook!
生まれた～ 生まれた～
It's born~ It's born~
あかんわ～
This is hopeless~
生まれ... リスポーンで生まれた～！
Born... Born by respawning~!
いえーい！
Yay!
ねー、今後もお待ちしております！
We're looking forward to more in the future!
お願いします、ラム丼ラム丼！
Please, lamb bowl lamb bowl!
いやいや違う違う違う！
No, no, no!
違うの、このステージでね...
No, on this stage...
え、コントじゃないの？
Wait, it's not a comedy skit?
違う、違うよ！
No, it's not!
コントじゃないんだ。ごめんね。
It's not a skit. Sorry.
ラ、イ、ブ！
Li-ve!
あ、ライブ！
Ah, live!
ライブ！ライブ！
Live! Live!
次の曲をね、聴いてもらったら、すっげー合うと思ってもらえると思うんだよね！
If you listen to the next song, I think you'll feel it really fits!
我々にシナジーが生まれるんですね。
So synergy will be born between us.
そう、化学反応が起こる！
Yes, a chemical reaction will occur!
はい、と思うので。行くぞ！
Right, so. Let's go!
行くぞー！
Let's go!
では聴いてください。のびしろ。
Then please listen. Nobishiro.
のびしろ
作詞: R-指定 作曲: DJ松永
Nobishiro
Lyrics: R-Shitei Composer: DJ Matsunaga
サボり方とか甘え方とか　逃げ方とか言い訳の仕方とか
How to slack off, how to be pampered,
how to run away, how to make excuses
やっと覚えてきた　身につけてきた　柔らかい頭
I've finally started to learn,
I've acquired a flexible mind
格好の付け方　助詞のこき方　鼻の据え方　愛想の振り方
How to look cool, how to use particles,
how to settle my nose, how to act friendly
油の乗りだした　煮え滾ってきた　だらしない身体
My body is getting greased up, it's starting to boil,
this slovenly body
祝われ方や　叱られ方や　下り方とか　綺麗なぶつかり方
How to be celebrated, how to be scolded,
how to step down, how to clash beautifully
もっと覚えたいことが山の様にある
There's a mountain of things I want to learn
のびしろしかないわ
I've got nothing but room to grow
俺らまだ　のびしろしかないわ
We still have nothing but room to grow
悪者扱い　して来た街で
In the town that treated me like a villain
悪者扱い　して来た大人へ
To the adults who treated me like a villain
変わりゆくこれ　片身の中で
Things are changing within this narrow space
尋ねても答えなら　イェイ　イェイ　イェイ　イェイ
Even if I ask, the answer is yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
去る者追わない　引き際引いて
I don't chase those who leave, drawing a line
丸く収めたい　角食いなして
I want to settle things smoothly,
dodging the rough edges
鏡の中で　笑ってるお前
You, laughing in the mirror
括れやしなかった　たったの三文字で
Couldn't be summed up in just three characters
日々を待つなら足取りで
Waiting for the days with my footsteps
自分の歩幅で闊歩して
Walking proudly with my own stride
たまに誤魔化し　また胡麻化し
Occasionally deceiving, then deceiving again
割と適当だった段取りで
With plans that were fairly haphazard
やっとわかってきたかも
I might have finally started to understand
このポンコツの操縦の仕方を
How to pilot this piece of junk
十九の時に不意に来た便り
The news that came suddenly when I was nineteen
もっとすがすがしい気持ち
A much more refreshing feeling
隅田川にかかる
Stretching across the Sumida River
勝鬨橋を渡る
Crossing the Kachidoki Bridge
左手にスカイツリー
Skytree on the left
右手に東京タワー
Tokyo Tower on the right
俺はその真ん中
And I'm right in the middle
サボり方とか甘え方とか　逃げ方とか言い訳の仕方とか
How to slack off, how to be pampered,
how to run away, how to make excuses
やっと覚えてきた　身につけてきた　柔らかい頭
I've finally started to learn,
I've acquired a flexible mind
格好の付け方　助詞のこき方　鼻の据え方　愛想の振り方
How to look cool, how to use particles,
how to settle my nose, how to act friendly
油の乗りだした　煮え滾ってきた　だらしない身体
My body is getting greased up, it's starting to boil,
this slovenly body
幸せの耐震速度は
The earthquake-resistant speed of happiness is
早くなるばかり
Only getting faster
傷が癒えていく速度は
The speed at which wounds heal is
遅くなるばかり
Only getting slower
人に期待をしないのが
Not expecting anything from people
今の俺の強み
Is my strength right now
手を引いても進める距離が
The distance I can cover even if I pull back
育って魂魂
Has grown, soul, soul
身の程を知るほどに
The more I know my place
胸を張り　いつものに
I puff out my chest, doing the usual
でも時に下で背伸び
But sometimes I stretch myself thin underneath
やっと大人げないができる歳
Finally at an age where I can act immature
小さな枠組み　ただの筋
A small framework, just a plot
縛られずにでも腹くくり
Without being bound, but with determination
あの日の俺が立ち止まることに　デカく聳え立つ
To the fact that I stopped that day,
it stands tall and huge
隅田川にかかる
Stretching across the Sumida River
勝鬨橋を渡る
Crossing the Kachidoki Bridge
重なるスカイツリー
Overlapping Skytrees
東京タワーど真ん中の頼りない背中
Tokyo Tower, the unreliable back right in the middle
サボり方とか甘え方とか　逃げ方とか言い訳の仕方とか
How to slack off, how to be pampered,
how to run away, how to make excuses
やっと覚えてきた　身につけてきた　柔らかい頭
I've finally started to learn,
I've acquired a flexible mind
格好の付け方　助詞のこき方...
How to look cool, how to use particles...
...腹の据え方 愛しの漕ぎ方
...the way I hold my ground, the way I pedal my beloved bike,
油の乗りに乗った濁った目した
with muddy eyes that are in their prime,
だわしない体が
my sloppy body...
嫌われ方や慕われ方や
the way I'm hated, the way I'm adored,
叱り方とか綺麗なぶつかり方
the way I scold, and the beautiful way I clash...
覚えたことが山のようにある
There are mountains of things I've learned.
伸びしろしかないわ
I've got nothing but room to grow.
(Wa!) 伸びしろしかないわ
(Wah!) Nothing but room to grow.
俺らまだ伸びしろしかないわ
We've still got nothing but room to grow.
「悪くないよねぇ？」
"It's not bad, right?"
「悪いね」
"It's bad."
ジャンキー
作詞・作曲：syudou
Junky
Lyrics & Composition: syudou
流行り廃りのない人生を探し続けていた
I was searching for a life that doesn't go in and out of style.
月火水木金土日 もっと夢中になって
Mon, Tue, Wed, Thu, Fri, Sat, Sun... Getting more obsessed.
もういいかよ 何回聞いたって
"Is it enough yet?" No matter how many times I'm asked.
まだだよ 全感帯行っちゃって
"Not yet!" Going through my whole sensory zone.
もういいよってバイバイしたって
Even if I say "That's enough" and say goodbye...
何だったんだ 黙超連覇
What was that? Silent over-winning streak...
何故分かち合ってんじゃ
Why are we sharing this?
着飾った愛を語ったって 行き詰まってジャンキー
Even if you talk of dressed-up love, you're a stuck-up junky.
燻って嫌になっていく 承認欲求は飽き飽きです
Smoldering and getting sick of it, I'm tired of the desire for approval.
本当飽き飽きです
I'm really tired of it.
飽き飽きです
I'm tired of it.
本当飽き飽きです
I'm really tired of it.
従って もっと夢中になって 固まってジャンキー
Therefore, get more obsessed and freeze up, junky.
疑って早く配ってた その劣等感に飽き飽きです
I'm tired of that inferiority complex you were so quick to suspect and distribute.
本当飽き飽きです
I'm really tired of it.
もうダメで単調なジャンキーは結構です
No more, I'm done with monotonous junkies.
代わり映えのしない毎日を燃やし続けていた
I kept burning through days that never changed.
月火水木金土日 ずっと立ち止まって
Mon, Tue, Wed, Thu, Fri, Sat, Sun... Standing still all the while.
興味ないと不完全と言って
Saying it's incomplete if you're not interested...
消耗品と散々荒らしちゃって
Ruining it like a disposable commodity...
等身大も寛大に掲げ通したんだ
I've held up even my true self with generosity.
黙超連覇 何透かしちゃってんじゃ
Silent over-winning streak, what are you trying to hide?
着飾った愛も固い愛と それはそれでジャンキー
Dressed-up love and tough love, both are junkies in their own way.
偏った愛に染まっていく 均衡方正も飽き飽きです
Getting stained by biased love, I'm tired of balance and integrity.
本当飽き飽きです
I'm really tired of it.
飽き飽きです
I'm tired of it.
本当飽き飽きです
I'm really tired of it.
従って もっと夢中になって 固まってジャンキー
Therefore, get more obsessed and freeze up, junky.
疑って早く配ってた その劣等感に飽き飽きです
I'm tired of that inferiority complex you were so quick to suspect and distribute.
本当飽き飽きです
I'm really tired of it.
もうダメで単調なジャンキーは結構です
No more, I'm done with monotonous junkies.
長い長い長い未来の想像描いてく
Painting a vision of a long, long, long future.
時代じゃない 時代じゃない 自分次第だってな
It's not the times, it's not the times, it's up to me.
笑っていたいし 夢中でいたいし 想っていたいし 歌っていたいよ 感情を
I want to keep laughing, keep being obsessed, keep caring, and keep singing my emotions.
着飾った愛を語ったって 行き詰まってジャンキー
Even if you talk of dressed-up love, you're a stuck-up junky.
燻って嫌になっていく 承認欲求は飽き飽きです
Smoldering and getting sick of it, I'm tired of the desire for approval.
本当飽き飽きです
I'm really tired of it.
飽き飽きです
I'm tired of it.
本当飽き飽きです
I'm really tired of it.
従って もっと夢中になって 固まってジャンキー
Therefore, get more obsessed and freeze up, junky.
疑って早く配ってた その劣等感に飽き飽きです
I'm tired of that inferiority complex you were so quick to suspect and distribute.
本当飽き飽きです
I'm really tired of it.
もうダメで単調なジャンキーは置いておいて
Put aside the hopeless, monotonous junkies...
永久に厄介なジャンキーで結構です
and I'm fine being a troublesome junky forever.
ひゃ〜、楽しいな〜！
Hyaa, this is fun!
ここまで出演してくれた
Thank you to all the guests
ゲストのみんなも、ありがと〜！
who've performed so far!
いやぁ、ライブもね、終盤に差し掛かってきたけど、
Man, the concert is entering its final stages, but
みんなはどれくらい…
how much is everyone...
この１年、どんな年だったかな？
This past year, what kind of year was it?
わためはね、とにかく、あっという間だったかなー。
For Watame, anyway, it felt like it went by in a flash.
いろんな人の、歌のライブゲストにも出させてもらったり...
I got to appear as a guest in various people's singing lives...
今年のわための記念配信にも、
And for my own commemorative streams this year,
いろんなたくさんのホロメンを呼べてね、とっても嬉しかったし、楽しかった、そんな１年だったな気がします。
I was able to invite many Holo-members, which made me very happy and it was a fun year like that.
あとはね、いろんな、企画？ギリギリわるくないわためとか...
Also, various projects? Like "Giri Giri Warukunai Watame"...
あと、角巻わための「Have a Nice Day」とか、企画とかに挑戦したり...
And Tsunomaki Watame's "Have a Nice Day", taking on challenges like those projects...
あとは今年もね、たくさん配信したし、
And also, I streamed a lot this year,
もう何より、駆け抜けた１年だったなと思います。
and more than anything, I think it was a year of running through it all.
ずっとね、わためいとのみんなと一緒だったから、
Since I was with all the Watamates the whole time,
本当に楽しかったよ。泣いちゃうよー。
it was really fun. I'm gonna cry.
わためいともそう思ってくれてると嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if the Watamates feel the same way.
いや、コメントでもね、「あっという間だった」とか、
Looking at the comments, "it went by in a flash" and
ハートとかもね、いっぱい送ってくれてるけど、やっぱそうだよね。
lots of hearts being sent, yeah, that's right.
今年、あっという間だったよね。
This year really went by in a flash, didn't it?
今年は、オリ曲も、去年ほどじゃなかったけど...
This year, original songs weren't as many as last year, but...
あの、なな、なんだっけ...なんだっけ...
Um... what was it... what was it...
もう、涙をこらえるので精一杯で、曲名が出てこないよー。
I'm so busy holding back tears that I can't remember the song titles!
あ、夢見る羊とか、君色ハナミズキとか、
Ah, "Yumemiru Hitsuji", "Kimiiro Hanamizuki",
あとは、カリちゃんとのね、ラップ２バージョンとか、もう４曲ほど、５曲ほどかな？作れて。
and the two rap versions with Calli-chan... I was able to make about 4 or 5 songs.
本当みんなのおかげです。ありがとうございます。
It's really all thanks to everyone. Thank you very much.
英語のラップにもね、頑張って、「もう、やだ、無理」って言いながら挑戦したり...
Even with English rap, I worked hard and took it on while saying "I hate this, I can't do it"...
作詞も、何曲か書かせていただいたり、
I also got to write the lyrics for several songs,
挑戦の年だったなと思います。
so I think it was a year of challenges.
この３年間、駆け抜けてきたけど...
I've been running through these past three years...
まだまだ、叶えたい夢や、
But there are still so many dreams I want to fulfill and
みんなと一緒にやりたいこととかも、たくさんあるから...
things I want to do together with everyone...
これからも、挑戦を続けていくという気持ちを込めて、歌いたいと思います。
So, with the feeling of continuing to take on challenges, I'd like to sing.
聴いてください、My song。
Please listen, "My song".
My song
手にしたもの以外が 綺麗に見えた
Things other than what I held looked beautiful
どうせこんなもんかと 口癖だった
I used to say, "I guess it's just like this"
薄ら笑いばかりが 得意になった
I became good at only thin smiles
けど 一番笑えるのは このプライドだ
But the funniest thing is this pride
一生懸命なんか 全部無駄だったんだ
Everything I did with all my might was all in vain
ああ もう嫌になった
Ah, I've had enough
逃げたくないって聴こえた これは僕の声
I heard a voice saying "I don't want to run away", it's my own voice
1回 10回 100回 1000回 挑戦は続けるや まだ足りない
1 time, 10 times, 100 times, 1000 times, I'll keep challenging, it's still not enough
手放してる やまない雨の中
Letting go, in the never-ending rain
ずっと考えて 考えて 考えて 見つけだせ 僕だけの正解を
Think, think, think constantly, and find it, my own answer
証明したいんだよな そうだろう
I want to prove it, right?
そうだろう
Right?
焦り上がる心拍数に 嘘つくように
As if to lie to the racing heart rate
自分を落ち着ける 皮肉はいらない
To calm myself down, I don't need irony
それも昂揚感に 置き換えたらさ
If I replace even that with excitement
今日もまた 挑むべきハードルが ほら 見えただろう
Today again, look, you can see the hurdles I should challenge
葛藤の隙間まで 錆びない生命を
To the gaps of conflict, a life that doesn't rust
捻り出せるか
Can I wring it out?
出ないのなら とっくに諦めてるよ
If I couldn't, I would have given up long ago
渾身の信念で 歌ったって 届くわけじゃない
Even if I sing with my whole heart and belief, it's not like it'll reach
素晴らしいかい 僕らの現実は残酷だ
Is it wonderful? Our reality is cruel
曖昧を削り取って 尖らせ また歌って
Scrape off the ambiguity, sharpen it, and sing again
諦める くらいなら 過去に捨ててきた
If I were to give up, I would have left it in the past
愛してたいよ
I want to love
立ち止まるたびに進みたがる足を まだ行こう
With my legs that want to move forward every time I stop, let's keep going
…もがいた
…struggled
小さくて頼りなくて不安定な歩幅が
Small, unreliable, and unstable steps
つながって歌になる 僕を聞いてくれ
Connect to become a song, please listen to me
みんな、ありがとう！
Everyone, thank you!
1回10回100回1000回 挑戦は続けるよ まだ足りない 手を待ってる
1 time, 10 times, 100 times, 1000 times, I'll keep on challenging. Not enough yet, waiting for hands.
止まない雨の中
In the unending rain
ずっと考えて考えて考えて見つけ出した
Kept thinking, thinking, and thinking until I found it
僕だけの正解を証明したいんだよな
I want to prove my very own answer
もし辿り着いたなら 誇っていいかな
If I reach it, can I be proud of myself?
4年目も一緒に歩いていこうね。
Let's walk together in our 4th year too.
最後の曲です。
This is the last song.
聴いてください。
Please listen to it.
新曲、Happy day to you!
My new song, Happy day to you!
Happy day to you!
作詞：角巻わため 作曲・編曲：堀江晶太
Lyrics: Tsunomaki Watame / Composition & Arrangement: Horie Shouta
今日は年に一度 特別な日
Today is a special day once a year
君と一緒に今お祝いをしよう
Let's celebrate with you now
ケーキの上 ローソク 火をつけて
Light the candles on top of the cake
おめでとう！ 笑顔が溢れるよ
Congratulations! Smiles are overflowing
産まれてきたこと
The fact that you were born
それは偶然？ 奇跡かもしれない
Is it a coincidence? Or maybe a miracle
でもせっかくなら 日々をもっと
But if we have the chance, let's make the days more...
happy! enjoy! さあ行こう！
happy! enjoy! Let's go!
雲の綿菓子食べてみたり
Trying to eat cotton candy clouds
魔法を使って空を飛んだり
Using magic to fly through the sky
誰かを救うヒーローになったり
Becoming a hero who saves someone
なんでもできそうな気がするね
I feel like I can do anything
そんな奇跡みたいな日々を
Those miracle-like days
ずっと もっと
Always and more
なんでもない日々は意地悪で
The ordinary days are unkind
くちびる噛みしめる時もあるよね
There are times when you bite your lip
落ち込んでへこんで浮かない顔
Feeling down, depressed, and looking blue
大丈夫 笑顔がこぼれるよ
It's okay, a smile will come out
産まれてきたこと
The fact that you were born
それを後悔しちゃう日もあるかもしれない
There might be days when you regret it
でもせっかくなら 日々をもっと
But if we have the chance, let's make the days more...
happiness! joyful! ほら行こう！
happiness! joyful! See, let's go!
小さな幸せ積み上げて
Piling up small happinesses
世界で一つだけの宝物
The only treasure in the world
君が生きた証 抱きしめて
Embrace the proof that you lived
産まれてきてくれてありがとう
Thank you for being born
君も、そこの君も一緒に
You too, and the you over there, together
同じ時代に生まれた奇跡たち
The miracles born in the same era
来年も再来年も一緒に
Together next year and the year after too
ここで笑ってお祝いしよう
Let's laugh and celebrate here
そんな奇跡みたいな日々を
Those miracle-like days
ずっと もっと
Always and more
皆さん、こんばんは！
Good evening, everyone!
ここで、角巻ニュースのお時間です。
It's time for Tsunomaki News.
なんと、この後10時、
Believe it or not, after this at 10:00,
角巻わためさん活動3周年記念グッズが販売となります！
Tsunomaki Watame-san's 3rd Anniversary commemorative goods will go on sale!
イエーイ！
Yay!
内容は、アクリルスタンド、
The contents are: an acrylic stand,
グラス、わためぇとぬいぐるみ、
a glass, a Watamate plushie,
そして、わためのうた vol.2.5の4点セットです。
and the Watame no Uta vol. 2.5, a 4-item set.
まずは、こちらの商品、
First, this product,
アクリルスタンドです。
is the acrylic stand.
実はわためぇと一緒にお出かけするように作ってあります。
Actually, it was made so you could go out with Watame.
めっちゃいい景色を一緒に見て、写真を撮りたいようです。
She wants to see great scenery and take photos together.
イラストは、佐倉おりこ先生に書いていただきました。
The illustration was drawn by Sakura Oriko-sensei.
みんなで旅行に行こう！
Let's all go on a trip!
続いての商品は、
The next product is...
グラスです。
the glass.
多分届くのが春以降になると思うんですが、
I think it'll probably arrive after spring,
その時にみんながゴクゴク飲めるように、
but I made it so everyone can gulp down drinks then
素敵なちょっと大きめのグラスにしました。
in a nice, slightly large glass.
イラストは、わためが書いております。
The illustration was drawn by Watame.
そして、3点目、
And the third item,
わためぇとぬいぐるみ。
is the Watamate plushie.
これ、実はわためが欲しかったんだよね。
Actually, I really wanted this.
わためぬいぐるみはいくつかあるから、
I have several Watame plushies,
ちょっとわためぇとぬいぐるみもないとなぁと思って、
so I thought I should have a Watamate plushie too,
あれ、画像まだかな？
Wait, is the image not here yet?
画像、あ、きちゃー！
The image... oh, here it is!
めっちゃ可愛い！
So cute!
今日のステージにもいたわためぇとそっくりです。
It looks exactly like the Watamate that was on stage today.
めちゃくちゃいい！
It's so good!
そしてそして、最後に、
And finally,
わためのうた vol.2.5です。
is Watame no Uta vol. 2.5.
今回はシングルくらいの曲数なので、
This time it has about the same number of songs as a single,
2.5とさせていただきました。
so I made it 2.5.
今日の配信で歌ったHappy day to you!も収録されております。
The song I sang in today's stream, 'Happy day to you!', is also included.
こちら動画にして投稿する予定がありませんので、
I have no plans to post this as a video, so
是非チェックしてみてください。
please check it out.
CDジャケットは、我らがふーみママに書いていただきました。
The CD jacket was drawn by our very own Fuumi-mama.
ママ、いつも本当にありがとう！
Mama, thank you so much as always!
本日24時から各種音楽サイトでも公開されますので、
It will also be released on various music sites starting from 24:00 today,
こちらもチェックをよろしくお願いします。
so please check that out too.
そして、フルセットを購入していただいたお客様には、なんと、
And for customers who purchase the full set...
角巻わため箔押し複製サイン入り、チェキ風ブロマイドカードと、
a Tsunomaki Watame foil-stamped reproduced signed cheki-style bromide card,
3周年感謝の特典ボイス2022がついてきます。
and a 3rd Anniversary gratitude bonus voice 2022 are included.
これは、買うしかありませんねぇ。
You've got no choice but to buy it.
ということで、以上が3周年グッズになります。
And that's it for the 3rd Anniversary goods.
わためいとのことを考えて、少しでも喜んでもらえるように、
I thought of the Watamates and to make you even a little happy,
スタッフさんとかと入念に打ち合わせをして、いいものにしました。
I had careful meetings with the staff and others to make it great.
是非チェックしてください！
Please check it out!
まだ、本編は続きます。
The main show continues.
その後アフターライブもあるから、遊びに来てね！
There's an after-live after this too, so come by!
以上、角巻ニュースでした！
That was Tsunomaki News!
わためー！こっちこっち！
Watame! Over here, over here!
早く早く！
Hurry, hurry!
はい、今行きまーす！
Yes, I'm coming now!
Chan Chan A Chiki Chiki Ban Ban
A Chiki Chiki Chan Chan A Chiki Chiki Ban Ban
A Chiki Chiki Chuki Ban Ban
A Chiki Chiki Ban Ban A Chiki Chiki Chan Chan
A Chiki Chiki Ban Ban A Chiki Chiki
Wow 洒落ついた
Wow dressed up,
皆気まぐれでツライ
everyone's so fickle it's painful.
酔えばテキーラ
If you drink tequila,
あらぬ妄想で 続々とピカッ
delusions will flash one after another.
夢はパンドラ
Dreams are a Pandora's box,
ほら開けたくなる
you'll want to open it.
皆期待してパーティーへ
Everyone expects to go to the party.
不夜城の山 登らなきゃ分からない
Mount Fuyajo, you won't know unless you climb it.
今宵は週末の宿命
Tonight is the fate of the weekend.
Chan Chan A Chiki Chiki Ban Ban
何も持たず楽しめ FEVER TONIGHT
Enjoy yourself with nothing in hand, FEVER TONIGHT
Chan Chan A Chiki Chiki Ban Ban
何度ムシャクシャしたって PARTY TONIGHT
No matter how frustrated you are, PARTY TONIGHT
Chan Chan A Chiki Chiki Ban Ban
愚か者ほどハートをガッツリ掴んで謳歌
The more foolish you are, the more you grab hearts and enjoy,
Chan Chan A Chiki Chiki Ban Ban
みんなスーパースターの卵さ FEVER TONIGHT
Everyone is a superstar in the making, FEVER TONIGHT
Glass up, Glamorous night
デーモンもだけど みんな入るならハンズアップ
Even demons too, if everyone is entering, hands up
Realize, Religious
Japanese Pretty 密かに舞い降った
Japanese Pretty secretly descended
Glass up, Gracious day
飲めばノリよく 開けっ放しで Say Yeah
If you drink, you'll be high, keep it wide open and Say Yeah
Rock step, All step jump
腕まきしなよ 熱くダンス Oh Yeah
Roll up your sleeves and dance passionately, Oh Yeah
いつも目線はちょっと臆病でチリ
Always looking a little timid and chilly,
エネルギー満たせ千本テキーラ
fill up your energy with a thousand tequilas.
空を空を高く飛ぶジューター 真っ逆さまに
A carpet flying high in the sky, upside down
…さま 従わないで
...Lord, don't follow
陰気じゃだめ インフでしたまえ
No to gloom, infect them
ダラダラする間に
While idling around,
エンディング人生
life comes to an ending.
未練はNO シャイニー軌道
No regrets, a shiny trajectory.
はにかみ草 創設ぜ
Establish the shy plant.
OH BABY 小賢しいね
Oh baby, you're so cheeky.
ハハハ 威勢的なら
Hahaha, if you're energetic...
前だけ向いてりゃいいでしょ
...you can just look forward, right?
燃えさかっちゃうけどいいでしょ
It's gonna flare up, but that's okay, right?
もっとスプレーを もっとバンバン
More spray, more bang bang!
明日が来るけどご機嫌はどうだ
Tomorrow is coming, but how's your mood?
ほらほら時代にそっぽを向けんな
Look, look, don't turn your back on the times.
いつまで経っても
No matter how much time passes,
半端もん！ はじきばん！
you're just half-baked! Pop!
チャンチャン アイチキチキバンバン
Chan chan ai chiki chiki bam bam
アイチキチキバンバン
Ai chiki chiki bam bam
アイチキチキチャンチャン
Ai chiki chiki chan chan
アイチキチキバンバン
Ai chiki chiki bam bam
アイチキチキチュキチュキバンバン
Ai chiki chiki chuki chuki bam bam
アイチキチキバンバン
Ai chiki chiki bam bam
アイチキチキチャンチャン
Ai chiki chiki chan chan
アイチキチキバンバン
Ai chiki chiki bam bam
アイチキチキチュキチュキチャンチャン
Ai chiki chiki chuki chuki chan chan
アイチキチキバンバン
Ai chiki chiki bam bam
アイチキチキチャンチャン
Ai chiki chiki chan chan
アイチキチキバンバン
Ai chiki chiki bam bam
愚か者ほど
The more foolish you are,
背徳数風車
the more immoral your pinwheels are.
チャンチャン アイチキチキバンバン
Chan chan ai chiki chiki bam bam
みんなスーパースターのたまごさ
Everyone is a superstar in the making,
出番だ！
it's your turn!
チャンチャン アイチキチキバンバン
Chan chan ai chiki chiki bam bam
アイチキチキチャンチャン
Ai chiki chiki chan chan
アイチキチキバンバン
Ai chiki chiki bam bam
アイチキチキチュキチュキバンバン
Ai chiki chiki chuki chuki bam bam
アイチキチキバンバン
Ai chiki chiki bam bam
アイチキチキチャンチャン
Ai chiki chiki chan chan
アイチキチキバンバン
Ai chiki chiki bam bam
アイチキチキチュキチュキチャンチャン
Ai chiki chiki chuki chuki chan chan
アイチキチキバンバン
Ai chiki chiki bam bam
アイチキチキチャンチャン
Ai chiki chiki chan chan
アイチキチキバンバン
Ai chiki chiki bam bam
アイチュキチュキチュキ
Ai chuki chuki chuki
b1zROCKFES My Song
at 22:15 ~ Membership only encore LIVE!!
角巻わため 3rd Anniversary Live 3周年記念ライブ
b1zROCKFES My Song
at 22:15 ~ Membership only encore LIVE!!
Tsunomaki Watame 3rd Anniversary Live